# Izhan Yameen

Software Engineer

Email: izhan.yameen25@gmail.com

+92-3328831270 Mobile:

linkedin.com/in/izhan-yameen LinkedIn:

### **Summary**

I have completed my Bachelor's in computer science from Federal Urdu University Karachi. Also, I am pursuing my master's degree in computer science from NED University Karachi. Currently I am associated with Habib Bank Limited as a Software Developer. Prior to that I was associated with Adamjee Life Assurance as a Mobile Application Developer.

I have used different JavaScript frameworks over the years mostly I have worked with React, Angular and Express JS. I have 3+ years of working experience as a software developer in different organizations.

# Experience

# **Software Developer**

**HBL** - Habib Bank Limited

Aug 2021 - Present

- Responsible for developing and maintaining web applications as a Frontend developer.
- Improved performance of an existing bulk account module by 60% by prefetching common data needed for each request to process.
- Added new modules in Angular project in an existing project. Used lazy loading of Angular while doing so. Also done bug fixes on an ongoing project of Angular
- In addition, I used Node-JS to create REST-APIs for my projects. I used Express-JS while working on REST-APIs.

### **Software Engineer**

Diya Interactive

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

- Responsible for developing and maintaining React Native applications
- Added "Insurance Plan benefits" and "PDF generation of Illustration of benefits" features in an insurance based mobile application

### **Mobile Application Developer**

Adamjee Life Assurance Co. Ltd

Nov 2019 – Jun 2021 (1 year 7 months)

- Developed reusable React components using Hooks and used third-party libraries such as Redux, React-Router, Material-UI and **Native Base**
- Build Android TV Standee Application using React Native.
- Converted UI design mockups with React Native
- Used Bootstrap for React Web application to make design mobile responsive
- Integrated Web APIs in Angular and React
- Maintained Existing Angular applications & used different Angular's built-in modules such as Reactive Forms and HTTP Client

### Skills

- **Angular**
- React
- Node-JS
- React-Native

### Education

# Master's Degree - Computer Science

**NED University of Engineering** and Technology, Karachi 2021 - 2023

# Bachelor's Degree -**Computer Science**

Federal Urdu University of Arts, Science and Technology, Karachi 2015 - 2019

### Certification

# **Diploma Certificate in Computer Science**

Aptech Pakistan Issued in Dec 2019

# Connect With Me

#### Medium

izhan-yameen25.medium.com

#### Github

github.com/izhan25

### Stackoverflow

stackoverflow.com/users/136011 06/izhan-yameen